Go, go! Move it, move it!
走，走，走！快！
Let's go.
走啦！
- Let's go!        - There's four of you.
-快点！        -一共四个人
- You can count. I'm impressed. Drive.        - Rule one: Never change the deal.
-你懂算术嘛，不简单，开车！        -规则一：不能改变约定
Deal was transportation for three men with a combined weight of 254 kilos.
约定好运送三人总重254公斤
Yeah? Well, this is a new deal.
破坏约定又怎么样！
An extra 80 kilos means we won't make it on the gas I allotted.
额外的80公斤意味着，我准备的汽油到不了目的地
- We'll stop for more gas.        - Every stop we make exposes us.
-那就停下来加油啊！        -每停一次车就曝一次光
Every exposure increases the risk of getting caught.
多曝光一次就多一分被捕风险
An extra 80 kilos means the shock absorbers I installed for this job
额外的80公斤，使得我精心调校的哥尼避震器
won't allow us to outmaneuver any police that might be chasing us,
无法确保甩掉追来的警车
which means, if there is a chase, we lose our advantage,
也就是说…，展开追逐战，我们讨不到便宜
increasing the chance of getting caught.
被逮的可能性也跟着升高
I don't want to get caught. You don't want to get caught.
我不想被逮，你们也不想被逮
Drive the car or catch a bullet to the brains!
安静开车，不然脑袋准备开花
- Then who drives?        - Shoot this asshole! I drive!
-那谁来开车？        -杀了这罗嗦鬼，我来开！
Not without the ignition code you won't.
没有启动密码开不了
Three men, 254 kilos. That was the deal.
三个人，254公斤，事前约定好的
- Three men. 254 kilos.        - Seat belts.
-三个人254公斤        -安全带系紧
See what I mean about the shocks?
了解我说的避震效果了吧？
Now it's time.
时候到了
Look out! Get out of the way!
让路！
Wrong way!
走错了，逆向！
Stop, Marcel, stop!
他们逆向行驶！，马塞尔停车！
Move away!
噢，让开！
Go, go, go!
快！快！快！
Shit.
他妈的！
If you don't mind, I just conditioned the leather back there.
拜托，皮椅刚保养过
- Take us to the drop point.        - Not yet.
-带我们到交货地点        -还不行
The cops!
条子！条子！
What are you doing? Don't stop now! Do something!
不要停车，想点办法！
- Come on!        - What are you thinking?
-快点，想办法        -你还在想什么？
Go! Go! Go!
开车
Do it! Now!
加速，马索
Your gun, please.
麻烦枪借我
Police! Stop! Stop! Police!
警察！不许动！
- You gave me too much.        - I need you to take us to Avignon.
-你付太多钱了        -请你带我们到亚维农
The deal was this far, no further.
约定送到这里为止，不行
The deal is the deal. Rule number one.
约定就是约定，务必遵守
- Rules are meant to be broken.        - Not mine.
-有约定必有违约        -我不一样
Let's go.
走吧
Get in the car. Come on! Hurry! Move it!
上车
Where's your yellow card?
你的证件呢？
I must've left it back in Nam, at the base.
我一定是把它留在越南的军营了
They all say that. Left it in Nam on the base.
留在军营里，他们都是这么说
Let me show you what we do to people who forget it.
让你看看我们怎么对待，那些忘记它的人
Oh, no, please let go of me.
不要，请你放我走
You gotta be punished for this. It's a fate far worse than death.
你应有此报，这命运比死还惨
Oh, hell. What could be a fate worse than death?
天啊，有什么会比死还惨？
The Argentinean government commits to meeting the IMF's target this year.
阿根廷政府决意要在今年，达到国际货币基金会订的目标
Yesterday in Nice, four men robbed the Alliance Investment Corporation.
昨日…，四名歹徒洗劫尼斯的亚联投资
One man died on the sidewalk. The others were apprehended this morning
其中一名死于人行道，其他三名亦已在今晨落网
when they took a wrong turn on a one-way street in Avignon
他们于亚维农因违规转弯，而撞上计程车
Police said, were it not for the poor driving,
警方表示，若非他们驾驶习惯不良，价值二千万欧圆的债券
would have been cashed and gone by this afternoon. In other news...
会在今天下午之前被盗领一空
I always say, the way a man treats his car is how he treats himself.
所以我常说，待车如待人
I'd say that's probably true, Inspector.
我相当同意，警官
You have a good sense of humor for a foreigner.
难得你这个外国人
Like the French. Sly wit.
懂法式幽默，法兰克先生
Just the right amount of flavor. Been out driving?
会心一笑，恰到好处，出去飙车？
Till they pass a law says I can't. Want to come in for a coffee?
除非修法禁止，要不要进来喝杯咖啡？
Thank you, but I have a lot of stops to make.
谢了，还有很多车要检查
- 88, to be exact.        - That's a lot of stops.
-88辆，正确的说        -的确相当多
A lot of 1999 black BMW 735s
有不少1999年份…
with 0-6 in the license plates to check out.
黑色BMW735车牌是06的
It's a very popular car with a certain type down here. You've seen them.
本区某些人很喜欢这款车，你该看过
They come over from Italy in very expensive suits,
他们穿着高级西装，从意大利过来
and young, pretty girls with big jewelry and too much makeup.
年轻女孩珠光宝气，浓妆艳抹
Very... Mafia.
十足的黑手党
There was a robbery. A getaway.
发生了一起抢案…，开车脱逃
Some very fancy driving.
驾驶技术很炫
Was someone in a 1999 black BMW 735?
开1999年黑色BMW735
With 0-6 in the plates.
车牌是06开头的
- Have you been to the city lately?        - Not for a while.
-最近有进城吗？        -没有
I love Nice. The food, the way they grill fish.
我喜欢尼斯，食物，烤鱼很棒
No place else in France does it the way they do in Nice.
全法国独一无二
And the women...
以及女人
I prefer the women there.
我喜欢那边的女人
They are more... complicated
她们比较…复杂…，相较于其他地区，你同意吗？
- I don't particularly like complicated.        - You like to keep it simple.
-我不太喜欢复杂        -你喜欢单纯？
- Why are you so interested?        - Oh, you know,
你为什么这么有兴趣？
ever since I'm a little boy, military people have intrigued me.
打从小时候开始，军人一直很吸引我
- I'm ex-military.        - I am an ex-little boy.
-我是退伍军人        -我是童年不再
Sure you don't have time for a coffee?
确定不喝咖啡？
Everything's always so neat with you, Monsieur Frank.
永远有条不紊，法兰克先生
- Nothing ever out of place.        - I'll take that as a compliment,
-随时井然有序        -我当这句是恭维话
coming from a man who pays attention to every detail.
出自钜细靡遗观察家之口
Maybe I'll come back later for that coffee.
或许我晚点过来喝杯咖啡
Door's always open to you.
随时欢迎
- Hugo gave me your number.        - Be brief.
-鲁波给我你的电话号码        -有话请直说
- I need a transporter.        - I'm listening.
-我在找快递高手        -我在听
- One bag, that's it.        - Dimensions?
-只送一个袋子        -大小？
- Be specific.        - One meter 50 by a half meter.
-请给我正确数字        -长一米半，宽半米
- Weight.        - 50 kilos, not more.
-重量？        -50公斤,就这样
- Destination?        - 24, rue de Luxembourg.
-目的地？        -卢森堡街24号
- You're delivering to Mr...        - Rule two: No names.
-送去给…        -规则二：不提姓名
- Time of pickup?        - Seven in the morning, at the front door.
-提货时间？        -早上七点，大门口
A package. 150 by 50, 50 kilos, 250 kilometers.
包裹一件，长一米半，宽半米，50公斤，距离250公里
Traveling within the speed limit, one stop for refreshments: 40,000.
不必超速，中途休息一次，四万法郎
Half now, half on delivery. Delivery will be at noon. If no one's there,
事前后各付一半中午交货
Once we make a deal, it cannot be changed or renegotiated.
一旦达成协议，内容不能更动
- Another rule?        - That's rule number one.
-又是一条规则？        -这是规则一
Do we have a deal?
同不同意？
- You're very precise.        - Transportation is a precise business.
-你非常精确        -快递是精确的行业
Flat.
爆胎！
Don't move. I won't hurt you, I'll just make a hole so you can drink.
不要动，我不会伤害，只是帮割个洞让喝点东西
Please. Please, come on.
拜托，不要动！
Come on. Drink.
喝吧
Slowly.
慢慢来
OK, OK, that's enough.
可以了
Good girl.
乖
I'll take the tape off. If you scream, I'll have to kill you. Understand?
我帮把胶带拿掉，叫我会杀了，懂吗？
I have to pee.
我要上厕所！
You want me to do it in your car?
你要我尿在车子里？
I'm gonna take my knife out, so don't scream, OK? It's to cut you free.
好吧，我有刀，不要叫，我帮松绑
You don't need your mouth to pee.
尿尿不用嘴巴
You have one minute.
一分钟
55, 54, 53, 52...
55…54…53…52…
Breaking the rules, Frank.
你在破坏规矩，法兰克
Not good to break the rules.
破坏规矩不好
15!
15！
Seven.
7…
Two. Time's up.
2… 时间到
Don't make me drag you out.
你要我用拉的吗？
Shit!
可恶！
No, please! No.
不要！拜托！
Rule three: Never look in the package.
规则三：绝不看包裹
Hope you enjoyed your pee cos it's your last on this trip.
尿干净了吧，下不为例
See what comes of breaking the rules?
看到破坏规矩的后果了吧？
- You're late.        - Ran into a little problem.
-你迟到了        -碰到一些小问题
Nothin' serious?
不严重吧？
Nothin' serious.
不严重
- You open the package?        - Rule three: Never open the package.
-你开过包裹吗？        -规则三：绝不看包裹
I like that. Rules.
我喜欢，守规矩
You can't get anything done in a world without rules.
没有规矩，万事行不通
You're a foreigner, right? Nice little thing you've got going for yourself.
你是外国人吧？，你这小买卖做得很出色
High class... good reputation.
高级，声誉卓著
- I didn't get your name.        - Rule two: No names.
-还不知道你的大名        -规则二：不提姓名
Of course.
当然
You don't count it.
你不数一数？
Why? Should I?
为什么？需要吗？
That's what you do, right? You deliver, no questions asked.
这是你的工作吧？，只负责送，不提问题
Why not?
送东西没问题
Weight?
重量？
- Maybe a kilo.        - Destination?
-可能有一公斤        -目的地？
Grenoble. 306, rue de Lac. A Mr...
葛诺柏市，拉克路306号，一位先生叫…
Oh, right. I forgot. Rule two.
噢，差点忘记，规则二
I like him.
我喜欢他
What the f?
什么鬼…？
Where is he?
他在哪？
You're like dogshit. You're everywhere.
出来，真是阴魂不散
Useless piece of shit!
法兰克，你这猪头！
I ask the questions, you answer them.
我问问题，负责回答
No long speeches, just keep it simple. Got it?
简单扼要，不要废话，懂吗？
- Who are you?        - My name is Lai. I come from Jap...
-是谁？        -我姓赖，来自…
I ask the questions, you answer them. Nothing more, nothing less.
我问问题，负责回答，不必多说，不能少说
You wanna try again?
想再试一次吗？
- What kind of shit am I in?        - Deep shit.
-我惹上了什么麻烦？        -大麻烦
Very deep shit. Those guys... Sorry. I won't say any...
超级大，他们…，对不起，我不再废话…
- Where are you going?        - To bed.
-你去哪里？        -睡觉
Can't think straight when I'm tired. Good night's sleep, I see things better.
一累我就头昏脑胀，睡好觉，问题就能迎刃而解
- Can I leave?        - Be my guest.
-我可以走了吗？        -请便
- Boss...        - Sh. Save your strength.
省点力气吧
Just tell me: Who did this?
跟我说，谁干的？
- The transporter.        - The transporter's dead.
-送快递的        -送快递的死了
He's not.
他没死
You believe me?
相信我
I believe you.
我相信你
And the police... they were here?
警察呢？来过吗？
- You told 'em nothing, right?        - Right.
-你没跟他们说什么吧？        -没有
Of course.
很好
You couldn't talk.
你不能说出去
Let's keep it that way.
最好永远都说不了
I picked them from the garden outside. I hope you don't mind.
外面花园摘的，你不介意吧
I didn't know if you like coffee or tea, so I made both.
不知道你喜欢茶还是咖啡，所以两种都准备了
I hope you like... madeleines.
希望你喜欢…，玛德琳蛋糕
Try one.
吃吃看
Careful. It's hot.
小心，很烫
Good?
好吃吗？
Let me.
我来
- I like it quiet in the morning.        - Yes, quiet in the morning. Me too.
-我喜欢宁静的早晨        -宁静的早晨，我也喜欢
I'm the same way. I like very quiet.
跟你一样，我喜欢一片宁静
Sorry.
抱歉
Are you looking for milk?
找牛奶吗？
- There's milk at the door.        - Stay, stay. I'll go.
-门口有牛奶        -你坐，我去拿
- And you are?        - The new cook.
-是？        -新厨师
Is Monsieur Frank in?
法兰克先生在吗？
- Is your invitation for coffee still open?        - Sure, come on, please. Sit.
-喝咖啡的邀请还有效吗？        -当然，请进，坐
- Madeleine?        - Homemade?
-玛德琳蛋糕？        -自己做的？
My mother made fresh madeleines every morning.
我妈妈以前天天早上亲手做
I smell them and my whole childhood comes back in one big flood.
这味道让我想起小时候
Like Proust. You ever read Proust, Monsieur Frank?
就像普鲁斯特，你读过吗？
He would've been a great cop. Real determined.
他很适合当警察，观察力超强
- Milk?        - Please, milk.
加牛奶吗？
Thank you.
谢谢
I used to have a memory like Proust, like a filing cabinet up there.
以前我的记忆力不输普鲁斯特，脑袋像个资料库
I'd see something and remember it like that.
轻易就过目不忘
Like license plates. I could see a plate
比如…车牌号码，看过就烙印在脑海里
Like this one.
好比…这一块
- That's mine.        - Ah, memories.
-它是我的        -过去式了
- So? Where's the rest of the car?        - I was hoping you could tell me.
-车子的其他部份哪去了？        -我正等着你告诉我呢
- It was stolen.        - Stolen?
被偷了，我到菲宿港买点东西
- When I came out of the market, it was...        - Gone. Did you report it?
-从市场出来，它就…        -不翼而飞？你报过案吗？
It was the first on my list of things to do today.
准备今天一早去报案
It's a long walk from Frejus. How did you get home?
菲宿离这很远，怎么回来的？
I brought him.
我载他回来的
I saw him walking along the dark road.
我看他走在黑漆漆的路上
A risky thing, picking up a stranger on a dark road.
黑暗中载陌生人很危险
He had a kind face.
他的脸不像坏人
- I didn't see a car outside.        - It's in the garage.
-我没看到外面有车子        -在车库里
May I see it?
我可以看看吗？
Pretty nice car for a cook.
厨师开这种车真奢侈
Some people have a problem with the Germans.
有些人不喜欢德国人
They are too aggressive, they take up the best beaches in summer,
太招摇了，夏天占据整座沙滩，饮食品味令人不敢恭维
I say, anyone makes such great cars can't be all bad.
但我说做得出这种好车的民族，不可能一无可取
I would say you should work out very well for Monsieur Frank.
对法兰克的直觉很准
Work out for both of us.
我们是相看两不厌
My intuition says this is probably a good time for me to go file my report.
我的直觉告诉我该回去写报告
- Where's the rest of my car?        - Oh, yes, I almost forgot.
-我车子的其他部份呢？        -差点忘了
It was blown to pieces at a rest stop.
在休息站炸得粉碎
What's left of it is down at the lab.
残骸在局里的化验室
They are trying to separate what was left of the two cops in the trunk from the rest of it.
他们正努力将两名警察的尸块，从残骸里挑出来
But you wouldn't know anything about that?
算了，反正你不知情
- Thank you for the coffee and the memories.        - Come back anytime.
-多谢你的咖啡和记忆        -欢迎随时再来
- Would you mind walking me?        - No.
可以陪我走走吗？
You have always been very quiet about your business. I appreciate that.
你做事一向不张扬，法兰克，感谢你为局里省掉很多麻烦
This business at the rest stop, it's not very quiet.
但休息站的事太嚣张了，除了车子被偷之外
Would you like to tell me something besides the stolen-car story?
你不能透露点别的吗？
If I had one, I would.
如果知道，我一定告诉你
May I suggest that when the two of you show up in my office after lunch,
午饭后麻烦两位到局里走一趟
that you have one - a better one than you currently have.
希望到时你能谈点别的，换个比较有内容的版本
You are the one he wants to see, not me!
他是来找你的，不是我
- Quiet! Please. I have to think.        - You were supposed to think last night.
-安静！我得仔细想想        -昨晚你就该先想清楚
Last night I had nightmares.
是啊，可是我昨晚恶梦连连
About a girl who came into my nice, quiet life, screwed it all up.
一个女孩闯进我的宁静生活，搞得我不得安宁
Everything she touched broke and every move became a catastrophe.
她碰过的东西不是坏就是毁
OK, sorry.
好啦，对不起
I'm still wondering if I want to know everything or nothing about you.
我不知道该氐琢私，还是该保持一无所知
- What?        - It's the quiet.
-怎么啦？        -好安静
I thought you liked quiet.
你不是喜欢安静吗？
Not this quiet.
静得出奇
You OK?
还好吧？
- No.        - Good. Let's go.
-不好        -很好，走吧
Go, go, go!
冲！
No, don't stay there!
不要待在那里！
Give me your hand!
手给我！
Come on!
快，进去，进去！
Come on, get in!
进去！
Lai, look, hang on. Do you wanna die? Get in!
赖，快点！不想活啦？
Calm down, OK? Don't worry. You OK?
进去！    冷静点好吗？，不用担心，还好吧？
- Stay here. I'll be right back.        - No. Wait! Wait!
-留在这里，我马上回来        -等等！
Put it on.
戴上
You OK? Sure? OK, let's go.
可以吗？确定？
Frank? Is this your house?
这是你的家吗？
Yeah, I guess.
算是吧
I should mind my own goddamn business.
我为什么要多管闲事！
Simple rule, simple little rule.
规矩，简单的规矩
There's gotta be some dry clothes in this house.
房子里一定有…，干衣服
"Don't open the package."
绝不可打开包裹
Nothin' but trouble, you open the goddamn package.
打开保证后患无穷
Frank?
法兰克？
- What are you doing?        - Making up for the trouble.
-在干嘛？        -想报答你
- Wait, wait. Why are you making...        - No more questions.
-等等，为什么要报答…        -别再问了
Wait. I don't like it when things get complicated.
等等，我不想越弄越复杂
You like things simple. Very simple.
你喜欢单纯，很简单啊
I'm not so clear about the house. Could you explain one more time? After I left...
房子出了什么事，请解释一下，再说一次，我离开后…
We walked on the beach, had a swim.
你走后，我们去散步，游泳
- Where?        - Past the point.
-你说在哪儿游泳？        -海角另一边
- Anyone else swimming?        - No. Did you see anybody else swimming?
-当时有别人在游泳吗？        -没有，有看到别人吗？
No, no one.
没有，一个都没有
So, you took a walk,
所以…你们去散步
had a swim on a beach where no one else was swimming,
然后游泳，在空无一人的海边
past the point where you can't see or be seen from the beach on either side,
在海角那边，看不到别人，别人也看不到你们
which makes witnesses a little hard to come by.
所以不太可能有目击者
That's the point of a romantic swim. Who wants witnesses?
那里好浪漫，谁想被看到？
- And then?        - We came back to the house, found it on fire.
-然后呢？        -然后回去，发现房子着火了
- Just like that? On fire?        - Yes.
无缘无故起火？
The 5,000 rounds of spent ammo my men found all around the house?
现场五千枚爆炸过的弹药，你怎么解释？
- Maybe they had the wrong house.        - Monsieur Frank,
或许是他们认错了房子
people with this kind of firepower
法兰克先生，拥有这种火力的人，不可能搞不清楚对象
- Who would want you this dead?        - I don't know.
-有谁非置你于死地不可？        -我不知道
- Any problems with a client?        - I don't have clients. I'm retired.
-你跟客户有纠纷吗？        -我没客户，我退休了
I live on my army pension, you know that.
靠军方给的退休金过日子
You've had the facts of who I am and who I was for years.
你知道的，多年来，你对我了如指掌
Any enemies you can think of? People from the past?
有没有任何仇人？，以前结下的梁子？
I left the past behind when I moved here.
我搬来之后，过去都丢开了
A past like yours you never leave behind.
你的过去怎么可能丢得开
- What are you doing?        - Computers know everything.
-在干什么？        -电脑无所不知
- You just need a password.        - Are you nuts?
-只要有密码        -疯了？
- We're in a police station.        - You always complain,
-这是警察局！        -你总是不断抱怨
except when we make love. Then you say nothing.
只有做爱时不发一语，哈罗！
Hello. See?
看到了没？
- So, where will you be staying?        - I don't know.
-你们打算住哪里？        -不知道
Well, my cousin has a small hotel.
我表弟有家小旅馆
- Thanks, but we'll manage.        - Without money? It will be hard.
-谢谢，我们自己想办法        -身无分文，不太容易吧
Here. It's not much, but at least you won't go hungry.
虽然不多，但不至于挨饿
Thank you.
谢谢你
- Where are you going?        - To see that guy.
-要去哪里？        -拜访那个砘
- Good luck.        - One moment.
-保重        -等一下
- You're not coming?        - No.
-你不去吗？        -不去
- But he blew up your car.        - I'll buy a new one.
-但他炸掉你的车子        -我可以再买一辆
- He burned your house.        - I'll rebuild it.
-他烧了你的房子        -我会重新盖过
- He tried to kill you.        - As far as he knows, he succeeded.
-他想杀你！        -目前他以为他成功了
Some advice... I don't know what you're into, but whoever wanted you dead thinks you are.
劝一句，我不知道惹上谁，也不在乎惹上谁
You have a free pass to start over. Here's the advice: Start over!
大可以重新做人，我劝，重新做人！
There are 400 people dying in a container on a ship.
有四百人命在旦夕，在一艘货柜船上
My father.
我父亲
My sisters.
我姐妹
The ship arrives today.
船今天会抵达
They will make my father a slave.
他们逼我父亲当奴隶
The only one who knows the container number is that guy.
只有那砘镏道货柜号码
- You're very good.        - What do you mean?
-很厉害哟        -什么意思？
From the moment you saw those pictures in my house, you set me up to get involved.
从看到我家挂的画，你就开始设计我卷入的事
Breakfast, giving the excuse to the cop to help me, one lie after another.
早餐啦，帮我骗过警方啦，一招接着一招
- Not everything is a lie.        - Name one thing that isn't.
-并非全部都是骗局        -举个例子
What happened in the house between us,
在你家…，我们之间的事
that was not a lie.
那不是虚情假意
You were a soldier. Yourjob was to save people.
你是军人，救人是你的天职
- Past tense.        - What does that mean?
-注意，那是过去式        -什么意思？
I got tired of seeing my best efforts turned into bullshit
付钱请我效力的人，不把我的努力当成一回事
- No one cared.        - This time, I care.
-没有人在乎        -这次我在乎
Thank you.
谢啦
No phone calls for half an hour?
半小时之内不接电话吗？
Hello. Surprise!
哈罗，没想到吧
Sit.
请坐
Put your hands where I can see 'em.
手放在我看得到的地方
Before we get to the heart of the matter,
谈正事之前
I have a question: Why'd you try to kill me?
我先问个问题，你为什么要杀我？
You lied to me. You opened the package.
你骗我，你开过包裹
You broke the rules, your rules.
你破坏了自己的规矩
Did you expect me to recommend you for anotherjob?
你想要我怎么办？，帮你介绍另一趟任务？
What's the ship number?
船号是多少？
Mr Transporter, we can both agree.
快递先生，我们都同意
I answered your first question politely. I won't answer any more.
我礼貌的回答了第一个问题，我不再回答任何问题
So I suggest you kill me right now.
我建议你现在杀了我
And go screw yourself.
然后去自寻死路
I can't find anything.
没有一点线索
Oh, poor Frank. What'd she tell you?
可怜的法兰克，她跟你说什么
We're smuggling people in containers?
我们用货柜载偷渡客？
- Lai's the perfect name for her.        - Mr Kwai's on the way up.
-我跟你说，她不愧姓“赖”        -赖先生正在上楼
Your father's here. He'll get a kick out of this.
你父亲来了，怎么自圆其说
- I thought your father was in a container.        - Yes. I mean, no.
-父亲不是在货柜里？        -对，我是说，不对
There are 400 people in that container.
货柜里有四百人
- Stay where you are!        - She's a real heartbreaker, isn't she?
-留在原地不要动！        -她让你心碎吧，法兰克？
Ten seconds, two choices. The information, or your brains on the desk.
十秒钟，交出资料或你的人头
- Now tell me I'm lying! Nine... eight...        - Lai, give me the gun.
-再说我说谎吧，9，8…        -枪给我
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不懂你在说什么
Five... four... three... two...
5…
One. Shoot.
1，开枪啊
- Liar?        - Would I kill my own daughter, Lai?
-来啊！        -我会不会杀自己的女儿？
Come on now. Put it down.
别闹了，枪放下
We'll talk.
我们谈谈
She thinks we're smuggling people in containers.
她以为我们用货柜载偷渡客
- Where do you get these ideas?        - Stay away!
-怎么会这么想？        -不要过来！
- Could you kill your own father?        - Please, I am begging you.
-敢杀自己的爸爸？        -拜托
- Stop what you are doing.        - I do what I do.
-求你别再干了！        -我就是我
I am who I am. I'll never change.
爱做什么就做什么，我不会改变的
So if you're going to kill me, kill me.
如果想杀我，动手吧
But if you don't, get this gun out of my face.
如果不敢杀我，不要拿枪指着我
- Give me.        - No!
给我
I know he's innocent. Oh, you have such a good heart.
我知道他是无辜的，的心肠真软
Always interested in saving innocent people. Well, here's your big chance.
老是想拯救无辜，给一次机会
Drop your gun and you will save one.
枪丢掉，简简单单救一条命
- Kill him!        - No!
杀了他！
- The police are coming.        - What now?
-警察正赶过来        -怎么办？
Take her.
带她走
Send in Leo. I need him to wrap something up.
叫里欧过来，我要他来收拾一下
There were 400 people in that container.
不是四百人
Only 395 made it here alive.
抵达时只有395人存活
- Inspector. Am I glad you're here.        - What is this?
-警官，幸好你及时赶来        -怎么回事？
This man used my partner's daughter to try and blackmail us.
他利用我合伙人的女儿来勒索
Luckily my security got the drop on him.
还好保全将他制伏
I want to press charges: Kidnapping, extortion, assault.
我要控告他绑架、勒索和袭击
- I know this man.        - I suppose in your business,
我认识这个人
- Now should I call my lawyer?        - We'll handle it.
-我需要请律师过来吗？        -我们可以处理
I'll expect all of you at my office for your statements.
请你们全部到局里做笔录
As soon as I contact my lawyer, we'll be more than happy to oblige.
连络律师之后，乐意之至
The doctor said you'll have a headache,
医生说你会头痛好几天，之后不会有什么大碍
I think you should be more concerned with where you are.
你应该多关心自己的处境吧
What got into you? You were always so careful.
到底怎么回事？你出奇的谨慎
- I've got to get out of here.        - The charges are filed.
-我得离开这里        -他们控告你的罪名
You will not be getting out for a very long time.
足以让你关上好一阵子
Assaulting a distinguished member of the business community,
袭击优良国贸组织会员
kidnapping his daughter, extortion...
绑架他女儿，以及勒索
I'm sorry, Frank. I would like to help you.
对不起，法兰克，我也想帮你
But if you continue with the same old story: I'm retired, living on a pension...
但是如果你还是那套老调，声称“我退休了，靠退休金…”
I need fresh, Frank. I need new.
给点新说法，法兰克，新版本
For once, I need the truth.
总得跟我说一次实话
- You know this for a fact?        - The girl told me.
-你说的是事实吗？        -那女孩说的
- You believe her?        - Yes.
你相信她？
In French, we have a saying: Never believe the cook.
法国有句俗话，厨子不可信
- She's not the cook.        - Oh. I suspected.
-她不是厨师        -我早就心存怀疑
- No one is perfect.        - You're saying you'll do nothing.
-法兰克，人都会犯错        -你是说，你不采取任何行动？
I'm saying I'm going to start an investigation.
我会展开调查
400 people could be dead already.
到时，货柜里的四百人全死了
But what am I supposed to do? There are laws.
我该怎么办？这里有法律的
- Sometimes you make your own law.        - Like you do?
-有时你得自己自创法律        -跟你一样？
It doesn't take me 12 months to do the job.
至少不用浪费一整年时间
Oh, yes, I know. That's what I admire about you.
是啊，我懂你的意思，所以我很羡慕你
All that army training, all that sneaking around...
军事训练，偷偷摸摸的技巧
A man like you could probably resolve this case in how long?
如果这个案子交给你处理，需要多久？
- 12 hours?        - Less.
-12小时？        -更快
Anybody moves and I kill him.
轻举妄动我就杀了他
If this is how you transport, I'm amazed you get any work at all.
如果都用这种方法送快递，我很怀疑你怎么有生意
Come on, give me a hand.
来帮个忙
- Maybe I should go with you?        - Thanks, but I'm better alone.
-或许我该跟你去        -谢了，但我喜欢单兵出击
That is a very small boat to fight a very big war.
应付大场面，这船未免太小了
You'll need it.
你会用得上的
Or maybe not.
或许你不需要
Shipment is cleared. Here's the paperwork.
货物齐全，这是相关文件
Take the highway all the way to the first exit, Lyon.
一路走高速公路到里昂出口
Go straight to the warehouse. We'll be right behind you, just in case.
然后直接送进仓库，我们跟在后面以防万一
OK, we are ready to go.
可以出发了
Lai, dear...
亲爱的
I spent thousands of dollars for you to go to school and learn English.
我花大把钞票让学英语
- The least you can do is speak it.        - I hate you.
-至少可以用英文跟我说话吧        -我恨你
I'm still your father.
我一样还是你爸爸
Get her out of here!
押她出去！
Give me a minute.
等我一下
Keep him alive.
不要杀死他
Let's go!
我们走！
No, don't!
不，不要开枪！
Good morning. You lost?
早
- I'm lookin' to do a little sightseeing.        - This plane is not for tourists.
-我想看看风景        -这不是观光飞机
I'm not a tourist.
我也不是观光客
Call this guy and tell him to meet me.
连络这个人，请他跟我碰面，塔科尼警官，马赛警局
Sure. Where?
在哪里？
Down there.
就在底下
Here!
在那里！
Move up.
超过去！
Now.
好机会！
Get closer.
靠近一点
- Steady.        - No, Dad, no!
-稳住！        -爸，不要！
Get away!
滚开！
Down!
下车！
Hands on your head. Move!
手放在头上！，走！
Watch her. If she moves or I don't return, shoot her.
看着她，如果她乱来，或我没回来，就杀了她
- To the water.        - I'm really not in the mood for a swim.
-往水边走        -我没心情游泳
March!
快走！
So how did a lowlife like you end up with my daughter?
你这人渣怎么搭上我女儿？
- Found her in a bag, where you left her.        - You know nothing. Move!
你不是把她扔在一个袋子里？，你懂个屁！走！
You got involved with the wrong girl, you dumbshit.
钓马子也得搞清楚状况，白痴
The delivery will be made, my daughter will get over it.
我会顺利交货，她会忘掉这些不愉快
If I'm lucky, maybe she'll see the light.
好运的话，她会回心转意
If she's lucky, maybe you'll get hit by a truck.
好运的话，她干脆被车撞死
- What do you know?        - She'll never stop being who she is.
-你懂什么？        -我知道她不会改变心意
She'll never be you or anything like you.
她永远不会跟你一样
She'll come around. But you won't be here to see it.
她会回心转意，可惜你看不到
I guess she won't be coming around after all.
可能连回心转意的机会都没了
- Turn around!        - I'd rather see it coming.
-转过来！        -我宁可吃子弹
Makes no difference to me.
反正我无所谓
He was a bastard, but he was still my father.
他是个大坏蛋，可是，他是我的父亲
Pretty impressive timing, Frank.
时间掌握得真精准，法兰克
I guess I underestimated you.
我想我低估了你